If you want to build an aircraft, you
need to procure thousands of suppliers.
Someone sends a confirmation of like,
hey, sorry, like this part is going to
arrive 2 weeks later. And if they missed
this email, hundreds of millions of
damage.
>> Procurement historically may have been
more in a box and now it's touching
legal, it's touching finance. It's
touching a bunch of different software
systems and people. The opportunity for
the AI native startup is to say, we're
going to own that entire endto-end arc.
>> No company and no enterprise starts with
fully autonomous negotiation agents from
day one. Why? because they don't trust
us and they don't trust the technology
from day one. And by having this unit in
the loop approach, we have feeding our
agent with all the feedback and all the
learnings and then they suddenly trust
us for like 10k negotiations, 20k
negotiations, 100k negotiations.
>> When you think about what a durable
vertical AI company looks like, what are
the qualities that you look for? It's
really really hard to forecast your moat
going forward. If you look back at all
the best businesses at the early stages,
they were
Welcome back to the A16Z podcast. I'm
Elena Burgerer. And today I'm joined by
Sema Amble, a partner at A16Z, and Vlad
Kyle, a co-founder and CEO of LEO, which
builds AI agents for enterprise
procurement. Sema, you recently wrote a
piece called the incumbents are coming
and it asked a question facing almost
every AI application company. If an
established software vendor already has
the customer and the data and the model
can work across its tools, where does a
startup have an advantage? And um we
have Vlad here and Vlad can really help
us understand where a startup has an
advantage. And so I think a a good place
to start is the cases for and against
the incumbents. So if a company can
connect a capable AI agent to the
software it already uses, where does
another application actually uh have a
use case and an advantage there?
>> Yeah, let me back up and frame it up a
little bit. So historically we thought
about there's the incumbent and then
there's the startup and they're they're
fight they're you know it's a it's a
fight between distribution and
innovation which you know to to co to
take my partner Alex Rampel's phrase. Um
however now there's like this third
piece which you're you're you're
pointing at which is um the incumbent
can layer on um one of the models on top
or and and then there's a much more
formidable competitor in the market. And
so why do you need an AI native startup
if you've got cloud force which is
taking cloud plus Salesforce and putting
the two together and then you know
you've already got all your data and
your your customers uh sorry your
employees are all used to using the
product so why another product um I
absolutely still think there's obviously
still a case for uh the AI native
startup and it really centers around the
fact that um the legacy incumbent is
limited to their system of record and
that record that they have and they're
not completing the endto-end job. So let
me put that like more concretely in an
example. Um so say you're um a customer
and they customer calls and says they
got charged after they got cancelled.
that um resolving that cancellation
history isn't just the you know customer
going into the chat and saying hey um I
got uh I got overcharged and the
response there it has to hit billing it
has to look at all the chat history it
has to look at the contract that's not
one system of record that's the
knowledge around that customer and
everything it touched and that's
something that one system of record
wouldn't touch however the opport
opportunity for the AI native startup is
to say we're going to own that entire um
end to end arc that endto-end arc. So
that could be in legal. So owning
everything from uh brief all the way
through trial. Um well I can talk more
about procurement but it's it's really
this concept of owning the end to end
end to end work.
>> Yeah. Uh Vlad, do you want to talk about
just kind of where where that does show
up in procurement? Like where a existing
incumbent plus a model just is
insufficient and what have you seen just
with the companies that you work with?
>> Sure. So like when we think about
procurement, I like I would assume that
most people think about like prices,
right? So like what is the end price
that we negotiated on? And surprisingly
the the record looks always very very
simple and very easy. it's just 8K
that's the result for example and um I
mean it's the same for sales right so um
even if um if I come to Sema and tell
her like hey we we now partnered up with
another enterprise um look at the
signature here for like this contract it
looks like very easy but like Sema
doesn't see like all the work behind it
right so like there probably like 30
stakeholder meetings happened 500 emails
20 excel sheets and um that's the same
for the counterpart procurement right so
you see in ERP system, 8K for aluminum.
Um, but you don't see that maybe the um
the supplier did like a push back and
asked for like um 10K. Um you don't see
that like a cost engineer had run like 3
weeks of Excel sheets and 3D modeling to
find out the prices of the um of the
part and everything else. Um so that's
what we see. like most of the work um in
procurement actually happens outside of
this um ERP or any system of record.
Yeah.
>> Yeah. Um, and I'm sure just in in the
workflow that you described, an agent
can do, you know, a huge number of
things and different kinds of agents can
do a large number of things, too. And I
actually I think that's a good bridge
into the next question, which is like,
you know, a year ago, I think a lot of
the incumbents were releasing chat bots
and that was kind of the extent of what
you would see. But Sema, in this piece
that you wrote, you you lay out four
different kinds of agents. retrieval
agents, which are kind of the the chat
bots that we're familiar with, process
agents, policy agents, and principal
agents. So, can you just walk us through
all of them and explain kind of what
changes in the kind of judgment that's
necessary across all of them?
>> Yeah. So, a year ago, um, I I I made
this meme, which was the slap on a
chatbot strategy, which is essentially
like all the incumbents effectively had
a a chatbot that sat on top of the
system record, which you could chat with
to retrieve information, maybe do some
light analytics. And that really um was
in that first bucket of what the
retrieval agent is. Um, and maybe let me
walk you through an example of what each
of like the retrieval, the process, the
policy, and the principle. Back to the
like customer um the the customer
support example just because it's very
it's easier to understand. So imagine if
you're a customer and there's a service
outage and you're calling in uh to say,
"Hey, I want to get compensated for this
service outage." the retrieval
assistant, which the incumbent may have,
is going to be able to pull up, yes, you
know, there this was what the contract
term said and um yes, there was an
outage and just verify that information.
It's pulling up information about the
customer. It's in the database and it's
just like sharing it back and and maybe
synthesizing. The second agent or the
second step in the agent um sequence is
the process agent. So that process agent
may be able to pull through an approval
of credit and say okay um based on the
our policy handbook um it was out from
these dates. Therefore we are say you
are entitled to um money and it can just
apply the bill and just do process.
There's no judgment involved. Then as
you keep going to the policy agent, so
the policy agent isn't just going to um
apply the process, but it's going to
say, "Okay, uh in this situation, it was
out for 20 minutes. That's enough to be
considered a significant outage." And
they're applying that judgment because
there isn't really like a strict
definition around it. And then the last
stage, which is the principal agent,
you're actually weighing um you know,
okay, should we offer more compensation
because that was a pretty terrible
outage and we want to reserve the
relationship and it's worth doing more
beyond even what a process or policies.
But the importance of these four things
is that most incumbents started out in
if at all in bucket one. Now, at least
they're marketing that they are moving
towards process and policy, meaning
they'll be able to apply more judgment.
And you know, if you look at what
they've they've launched, um these are
workflow agents that will help you get a
document signed or um input information
from a transcription or things like
that. They're very much still limited
to, I would say, retrieval and a little
bit of process. They've not gotten into
more judgment. And I can get into why
like there are all sorts of incentives
uh that are preventing them from that.
But the incumbents are trying and I
think what they're not able to do
they're like some of them are think okay
let me partner with open AI anthropic
one of the labs and try to build out um
take that model capability and
complement what they have um and
superpower it supercharge it I should
say.
>> Yeah. Well do you want to say why sort
of some of the incumbents are holding
back?
>> Yeah. Okay. So there I would say they're
holding back but they are held back.
Okay.
>> Um yeah I I'm sure they they want to be
full force but there's probably two
pieces. One they have this advantage of
distribution right they have the
customer trust which enables them to
then sell more products with the
customer. So take Salesforce when Agent
Force launched uh it was very easy for
customers to say yeah I'm going to sign
up for the Salesforce agent especially
if it was offered at almost no extra
cost. Um, and so they have this trust,
they have the distribution, it's often
pretty seamless to turn on the product.
The flip side is there's all these
internal incentive issues, right? Which
is if you start getting into more
complicated agents, it's um it's a it's
an internal conflict with an existing
product that's offering workflow versus
you're resolving the work. And those are
two products that are um like if you're
solving a customer support issue end to
end versus providing uh um a workflow
for a support agent, a human agent,
those are different buyers. How do you
um you know those two teams are in
conflict and then on top of that I think
from a sales perspective like what are
you selling to the customer? And then
oftentimes in the classic like incumbent
issue, right, is like there's two uh two
VPs, right? and they're different orgs
and they're selling different products
and like they will never be able to uh
figure out what the the right set of
incentives and the right person to sell
to. But anyway, so there's all these
sort of classic incumbent issues I think
that the incumbent also runs into.
>> Makes sense. Um Vlad, where across this
this kind of spectrum of retrieval
agent, process agent, policy agent,
principal agent, where where does LEO
sit?
>> Yeah. So like we span across like I
would say like all of those categories
and it really depends on the complexity
and the risk um our agents take right.
So there
>> sometimes we um can like we already have
use cases where we run fully
autonomously um sometimes you have the
human in the loop. It really depends on
like the budget approval how like how
how complex and how how risky this is.
Um but maybe like coming back to what
Sema said about trust for for for the
incumbents like you talked about like
internal trust. I think there's like
also an external trust thing, right? So
like how do you convince someone to go
through from hey just like an agent that
retrieves some information and maybe
runs processes to do to do like
something completely autonomously is
like obviously there's like a product
component to it but mainly is a people
component. So they need to trust you. Um
and like we as a startup scale up we
have to earn the trust. Incumbents
already have the trust but this also
means they like they can destroy the
trust if they ship something like too
early and the product maybe doesn't work
or it's bad or like works um decisions
um in in a bad way. So that's um that's
that's what we we can do. Um and then
interestingly or what was like really
surprising for us like those process
agents um actually became kind of like a
side quest um for us because it like
when we talk when we look at the invoice
process um or like invoice agents as a
process. So you we we retrieve some
informations um you match this across
like other documents and then you push
this back to um SAP or Oracle like a
very clear um clear process um and then
we figured out okay that's like 100% of
the software market right so that's
that's invoice software um that's how
you build it today but it's actually
only like 20% of the work of the job to
be done of the problem because 80% of
the problem is like um what if like what
does the invoice is fraudulent. What if
there's like a mismatch? Like what did
what is like if we don't take the happy
path? Um and so we like um very fast
shifted to to the next step of agents
like doing those doing those exception
um um exception handlings. Um and we
convinced the customers by um I think we
got like lucky being like always
slightly ahead of the curve. So we were
able to to pitch the next generation of
agents. So for example like when we
started out 3 years ago it was like just
retrieving a document like not
impressive at all today but like three
years ago this was in like crazy
impressive. Um so we pitched this to
customers we find out okay that's a real
problem that's a use real use case they
would pay for and then we were able to
ship this some weeks later. Um and in
the same way we are doing this now for
the next step for process agents and for
like fully autonomous agents and for
longrunning agents. um we are pitching
this to them, finding out it's a problem
and then we're able to ship this very
fast.
>> I think an interesting point on trust is
this internal versus external trust. The
other lens on that is yeah so you need
your customer to buy the procurement
software and trust to use it for their
internal processes. But one of the
really interesting things when we first
met Vlad was that they're doing they're
also doing the negotiation. So you have
to trust that the LEO agent is going to
then interface with a third party and uh
and there is that piece of trust. Um and
of course I think a lot of people feel
burned by the incumbents and like you
know they're pretty limited and haven't
been able to do what they've marketed
they've had in the past. So but putting
that aside like I don't know maybe Vlad
I'd love to hear a little bit how you
convinced the customers to to trust an
AI agent to now take on negotiations.
>> Yeah. And can when you do that, can you
also just like paint the picture of like
what's involved in procurement and who
who are your customers? Um and and what
kind of sort of legacy systems are they
used to?
>> Yeah. So like when we um when you think
about procurement, you like maybe just
think about like purchasing or like you
when you look at like B2C world like
just you buy something. Um but actually
it's like a very intense process process
which like runs the economy, right? And
it includes multiple stakeholders and a
lot of stakeholders and a lot of um um a
lot of departments um legal, cost
engineering,
um obviously procurement, finance um all
of them have to work have to work on
this um um on this decisions and
essentially like when we um
like I think I think the reason is like
how how we convince them is like what I
um already said said earlier on. So like
we we're like always a little bit ahead
of the curve. Okay. So we knew the
technology is coming. So we like even
before CHBT came out um like we we just
started a few weeks before like this
CHBT breakthrough. Um, so we already
heard all of the all of the problems.
Then we hear the the hype in the let's
say like tech bubble and we were able to
pitch this enterprises and we quickly
figured out okay like this is a this
could be like an interesting use case
like just chatbot applications or
retrieval agents um document processing
um and then we we are able to find out
the problem and then ship this quickly
to them. And then obviously like this is
like the people factor of like trusting.
So we we telling them something about
and then we're able to really ship
something in production. Um but then
there's also like this product
perspective where we have um a lot of
like evils in place, right? So like we
um the like no company and no enterprise
starts with fully autonomous negotiation
agents from day one. No one does that.
Um why? Because they don't trust us and
they don't trust the technology from day
one. Um so you have like a very easy
approach of like um having a like human
in the loop and this is like extremely
helpful for us because we see like we
have like let's say like the perfect
negotiation agent which is like overall
the perfect procurement negotiator but
we don't know exactly how a fortune 10
enterprise like the specific fortune 10
enterprise operates and by having like
this human in the loop approach we are
feeding our agent with all the feedback
and all the learnings um and then they
suddenly trust us for like 10k
negotiations, 20k negotiations, 100k
negotiations. Um, and then you also have
like other um other agents that are like
more longunning. So when we talk about
like multi-million dollar negotiations
where you analyze complex 3D models and
technical drawings um there we on
purpose have always experts in the loop,
right? So there's an agent running for
multiple hours and then we ask for
feedback of the cost like cost engineer
and then it does the next um the next
work um and so on. Maybe just to double
click on that, how do you what where do
you put the human in the loop on the
like negotiation side? Uh you mentioned
the cost engineer, but like if I were
you were going back and forth on a deal,
is it mostly around the like uh you know
data for you know something like cost
engineering or is there anything else
where you have humans in the loop there?
>> So again depends on the level of
negotiation right. So like we have to
distinguish between like um negotiations
where you just like a negotiation where
in u like where enterprises they never
did those because they didn't have the
capacity but by by by deploying agents
they can just um capture savings that
they were unaware of right so they they
like before agents or before Leo they
just didn't care about everything which
happened below 50k right so you can just
like this is maybe a hack for like other
startups you can just send um an
enterprise an invoice for 40k they will
probably not negotiate because they
don't have the capacity to do so. Um um
except they have leo agents then we are
going to negotiate um against you. Um
but other than that they are just like
just um just paying that. And obviously
there the risk of like like what is the
risk of like you don't you didn't ne
negotiate at all. So what is the risk
now of having a bad negotiation agent?
Nearly zero, right? So um maybe we miss
out on some negotiations but like it's
better than nothing. Um but still um in
like in we're talking about business
relationships and business relationships
are not always about the cost and the
money, right? So maybe you're not
spending a lot on the vendor. Um but
maybe you you're like you need this
business relationship, right? So good
example might be like podcast or
marketing services. Okay, that's like
probably like a a friction of a um of of
the spend, but you don't want to like
you have a clear business relationship
with with someone like setting up the
studio. Um and you don't want like like
a random some random people doing that
because they already know how how A6
operates and how you want to record all
the stuff. Um so there we have human and
loop um approaches um where like
procurement people care about the
relationship. So they care about the
voice of tone and and how it works um
but mostly autonomously um and then we
have the other set of agents where we
always have um a human in the loop
approach and it's like um there like
multiple steps in like negotiating. It's
also like it's not only the price,
right? It's also like um how is the
contract design? So we talking about
legal, how is like um collection design?
So we we talk about finance obviously
like cost structure. So we're talking
about really like cost engineering. Then
we talk about commercials. Um that's
procurement. Um and those are not back
office people. Those are like highly
trained um people where they have very
specific knowledge of a very specific
process of a very specific company and
very specific industry. um and they feed
are those longrunning agents of LEO with
with those insights.
>> That's another example of how
procurement historically may have been
more in a box and now it's like okay
it's touching legal, it's touching
finance and it's touching a bunch of
different software systems and people
and both specialists and more
generalists.
>> Yeah. Um, can we can we map this on to a
specific uh c like not a specific
customer but a specific vertical like
I'm a drone manufacturer. I manufacture
humanoid robotics or something like
that. Like how many parts do I have to
you know order and procure? How many
factories am I touching? How many
suppliers am I touching? Just all of all
of those things. if you want to pick
maybe Vlad a vertical that um you know
is is just managing all of this
complexity with Leo and and just kind of
take us through what their experience
is. I think that would really help just
illustrate exactly um just everything
that you touch
>> again like when we like when we as Leo
when we talk about procurement of
purchases like we don't talk about like
laptops and pencils okay like we think
like that's solved also by Leo agents
but that's easy we solved this like
three years ago um we talk about like
when we like you want to build an
aircraft or robots or drones or even
like we now like doing a podcast about
um again like AI hype but even AI needs
to be built right so you data centers.
Um, and like building means procuring
like someone needs to like if you build
an aircraft, you need to procure
thousands of suppliers. You need to
build a factory to build this airplane.
Um, and like really small frictions can
have like a crazy impact, right? So like
there's a like if you're running a very
large project of like building a data
center, building an aircraft, if there's
like one specific part which arrives 2
weeks later, this can have like a damage
of like hundreds of millions of dollars
um and postpone uh and postpone the
project. Um so like all of all of those
that's why like all of those decisions
have to be co coordinated. Um and one
part is like you you need to figure out
like what you need with what suppliers
you work. um what are like what is like
the best supplier to um to like to to
get this part. And then once you decided
all of the stuff, there's like all this
operational um back office um stuff
behind it which might sound like
unnecessary and boring but again like
operational means someone sends a
confirmation of like hey sorry like this
part is going to arrive 2 weeks later
and this is like one of 500 emails um in
the Outlook or Gmail um of a procurement
manager and if they missed this email
hundreds of millions of damage done and
this h like this happens regularly
because the only thing they store in
their um system of record is then just
the date, right? So like it will like
not like not this Wednesday, next
Wednesday. That's what you see in the
system, but you don't see like like
maybe that's okay, but maybe that's a
$100 million damage and someone has to
decide that. And that's that's also what
our agents are doing, right? They are
not only retrieving the information,
they are then making the decisions um or
like does this have an impact? What kind
of impact and how can we resolve this?
>> Yeah. um when when you are sort of so
deeply embedded in the physical world um
what what kinds of you know physical
world problems can you intervene with
like some things I would think are just
like unsolvable you know like let's say
you have a shipment coming in and a
bunch of stuff like falls off the ship
or the straight is closed or whatever
like they're there they're they're kind
they're things that like you can't do
and obvious Obviously there are things
that you can do. So, so where where can
you intervene and where does that really
make a difference?
>> But but that's like actually it's about
like probability, right? So obviously
like you can't like you can't change if
um if like some like if there's like a
damage on the ship like every every
example that you manage like you um you
can't um change that but you can if you
have like all of the context you can
predict that.
>> Mhm. um because you can predict like how
um how reliable is a supplier. Okay, so
they're like there are ways on like
protect the goods that you're shipping.
Um and if you have like all the context,
you have like one supplier where like
20% of the goods are missing and then 1%
of the good is missing. Um and maybe
like this one with 20% is like 10x
cheaper. But for this use case, it's
fine for you to pay 10x the amount um
because you have like a higher
probability that this thing actually
arrives. Um so and this is the powerful
thing because you have like context not
only within one enterprise. Um so we
like we talked about like multiple
stakeholders but there's also context on
the outside world, right? So just the
agent should like have context of all
the news out there. um maybe even having
like context of like some bets like on
poly market I was like okay those
disruptions are going to happen um then
like um information about like on the
supplier side on the seller side on the
demand side and by combining all of
those contexts um I wouldn't say that
there is a limitation um in the long in
the long run obviously um like today we
have like different sets of like
probability but we can we can help
throughout the process and this is what
we are building um building at Leo right
so it's much bigger than just
procurement inter company it's more like
intra company and like how um how are
like businesses like how enterprises are
doing business with each other so like
buyer and supplier side
>> you describe LEO as a as a multi- aent
system so can you describe what the
different agents are doing
>> one level is that we um that Leo agents
spend across like all those four
categories that that Sema mentioned um
in her in her article and um it again
like depends on the um on the risk and
the complexity. Um so we use like all of
them. So like multiple agents um but the
other thing is that like in in order to
do a job end to end those agents need to
share information um with each other.
They need to do this in like a very
specific order. Um and when we talk
about like a multi- aent system this is
essentially what we are We are solving
like the task end to end and because the
also like human level task involves
eight people, eight stakeholders um and
maybe like three departments and five
different um software tools. Um we need
to cover like all of those to to do like
the job end to end and those agents need
to then communicate with each other and
only with a multi- aent system you can
do a job end to end. Um when we started
out we um like started off with like an
retrieval like more like a co-pilot
obviously like 3 years ago but then the
next step was like a single agent but
then we very quickly discovered okay
like that's like you can't solve an um
you can't solve in like negotiation even
um without having a contract um agent
without um maybe like having having an
agent looking at the news and everything
that I described before. Um so that's
what yeah that's what we define as a
multi- aent system. So if you have like
a bolt like an airline company needs to
procure a bolt for say you know Boeing
needs to procure a bolt what exactly is
that process for procuring the bolt and
like where does LEO step in on that
process?
>> Yeah so like this is like one of one of
the um one of the purchases where that
we can like run fully autonomously and
we can do this because of this multi-
aent system. So like first of all
someone has a demand right? So they need
to um somehow communicate it and even
like this part is extremely complicated.
Um so you need to call someone maybe you
like you like you open up your laptop
because you're like a construction
worker. You open up your laptop only
every second week. Um and now you are
required to like work with SAP um or any
other like um EIP system. So you can't
even like issue the demand. So this is
like how we make it very easy. So you
like you you you take a photo like you
you you upload a quote an Excel sheet um
and that's actually everything that you
that you should know about procurement
like no one cares outside of the
procurement department about like
categories GL accounts framework
contracts no one cares um we in the
procurement will care but no one outside
that cares and then our agents take off
and they're like they check the
inventory they find out okay they they
ask another plant okay can we like can
we source those um those bolts
internally no okay then I'm calling the
um am talking to the sourcing agent
finding out do we have internal
suppliers do we have external suppliers
then some like another agent has to
draft the RFQ send out the RFQ over um
over email then bunch of emails arrive
some of them are like completely
nonsense some of them are like just in
the email some of them are PDFs some of
them are Excel sheets we retrieve those
informations um then we do like the next
step oh maybe like based on our price
benchmarking there's an opportunity to
negotiate
Um and then then we have like agents
that essentially decide on the next
step. So negotiation could mean
strategic negotiation with a human in
the loop. This could mean autonomous
negotiation. This could mean auctions
and e auctions calling then the specific
agent doing the negotiation. Um and then
like doing this like end to end think
about like confirming the order,
shipment tracking, um invoices. Um and
we we are able to run this like fully
autonomously capture like all the
context. Um and then obviously the next
powerful thing is do this for like more
complex um parts where we talk about
like direct procurement um where we um
where we also operate. Yeah.
>> What what's uh direct procurement?
Yeah. So like um essentially like
everything I just described is um the
main goal is here automation, right? So
you can like run this process fully
autonomously and then throughout the
process you can like generate even more
savings, right? So it's not like so we
look at this like okay what is like this
like end to like job to be done? How
does it look like? So like what are they
doing like thousand times a day but
actually they want to do it like zero
times a day. We've like run like fully
autonomous agents, but there's like also
opportunities of like what are they
doing zero times a day, but if a
business would do this thousand times a
day, that was that would have a crazy
P&L impact. Autonomous negotiations on
um spend they never negotiated before.
Um so, so this is um and this is like in
the indirect procurement part like think
about um MRO parts, building a factory,
the bold example that we did. Um but
also laptops and pencils, marketing
services, someone who needs to build up
this podcast studio. Those are like all
indirect. And then we have like direct
parts. Um this is like when you build an
airplane. Those are like all the
suppliers that actually um that you
actually need to build the airplane um
or to build the drone or to build the
robot. Um and then we don't talk about
50,000 suppliers. We talk about 100
suppliers or 2,000 suppliers maximum.
Um, and those are like extremely
strategically important. Um, and you
have maybe on one supplier
like 1 billion of spend. So you don't
want to run an autonomous negotiation.
You want to run a negotiation which
which takes 3 months and where you're
like crazy prepared and where you have
engineers on your team analyzing, okay,
what's the indicy for aluminium? What's
the indicy for oil? Um, how did the
price change? Um, so you like really
take over like all of those drawings.
you check the quality um of this part
and this is what like where it gets like
really exciting deploying deploying
agents.
>> Yeah. And and for something like that
presumably like you'd have the expert
engineers and the other procurement
people kind of more as the front of
house and like the agent is more back of
house. Is that the idea or is the agent
like actually it's like you you sit
across the table and you're shaking
hands and it's like the robot instead of
the human who's like negotiating like um
is so yeah is it is it more back of
house or is it like still front of
house? It it's it's obviously more back
of house, right? Because you like
because you like
>> need like these complex multi-million
dollar negotiations and and that's
that's again like a beautiful example.
90% of the work is preparation.
>> Like the end result that you see in your
system of record is like oh instead of
like 1 billion I paid $900 million.
Okay. But like there's like three months
of preparation and like 10 people
working full-time on that. Um and
obviously this is like happening in the
um in the back. Actually we have some
use cases where um it's also like h like
helping in real time. So think about um
let's assume we would now have a
negotiation and I have like a pro
perfect preparation the same as like
with like those um those those notes um
those notes that we are having here um
imagine like while we are negotiating um
I would have like real time insights on
my screen popping up um where you tell
me the indicy for oil changed 10%. So
like it's increased by 10%. So that's
why we need to increase the prices by
10%. And I would have like an initial
like an an immediate popup with like
that's true like oil increased by 10%
but the product um has only 30% um of
oil contained. So like you you can you
shouldn't increase the price by 10% but
maybe only by 4%. Um so yeah there are
like exciting use cases also like in in
the real life um part. Yeah, we we know
that you know companies like Harvey and
Dakagon are really fine-tuning models
now. Um what what kind of underlying
models do you use and and how do you
approach things like fine-tuning or or
harnessing?
>> Yeah, so like we believe like you can so
like we use um multiple models from like
all um all providers and we really see
this as a like obviously like as a
commodity, right? So they like have um
really good like general business
purpose. So like reading creating a PDF
and like creating creating Excel sheet
like all all of this stuff. Um but we
also believe that like for some use
cases you um you you can get extremely
far with like combining the foundation
model with a with a hardness and you can
maybe reach like 100% of like the job to
be done. Um but there are also some use
cases where you can have like the best
foundation model, the best harness, um
whatever that means, but like um and the
best harness, but you still can get only
to 80%. Um and like I would say like
good examples for that is like for
example what um when we talk about
negotiations what like cost engineers
doing, right? So they're like analyzing
drawings and then they're like defining
okay what should this um this part
actually cost like and that's why it's
called like should cost modeling. Um and
there's um there is definitely like an
opportunity where we like thinking and
already started um um
fine-tuning the model to get then to um
to get them to to 100%. And this part
another example is like price
benchmarking um where think about like
the the like you would have a quote and
in a perfect world you would just drag
drag and drop the quote somewhere and
you would get the perfect price but it's
ex like and all those like all those
informations they're like not publicly
available right so there's all like
those are like all proprietary data
based on like one um one enterprise or
like across multiple enterprises so like
general purpose models can't train their
models on that. Um, so what we are like
what we are thinking about is like maybe
like not training just an LLM, but I
think like what we see now with models
like Jeff um or so popping up where you
have like an um you train it on like
text data but the out like the the
output is actually like an outcome um or
just like the perfect price. Um, and you
can't do this with harness because like
if you would give me like an um a quote
from BCG and a quote from McKenzie, they
they could do like the exact same work,
but this could be like a 10x different
price and I would have like no idea like
what is better. But if you give this to
a procurement manager, he would like
initially have a gut feeling or like
okay like this quote makes sense. Um or
like I think I think like good examples
again like content creation like always
like I don't know like how much I should
pay someone for creating a video. Um but
there's like a gut feeling behind it. If
I ask like another video creator of how
to um how to do that but if you ask them
to write down the rules they can't do
this because it's like just like gut
feeling and instinct. So, and that's
where we see a lot of opportunity
actually um training an agent but not
maybe like a classic LLM but more exact
like again like what what companies like
um or like models like like Jev are now
doing um on the outcome based so we have
like price benchmarking short cost
modeling. Yeah.
>> Um Sema uh we've talked a little bit
about how labs are really moving into
industry specific work or working with
incumbents to do this. um when you think
about what a durable vertical AI company
looks like, what are the qualities that
you look for? One is around, you know,
owning the endto-end work that we're
talking about, building up this data
asset and being able to do um something
that uh hasn't been done before. In many
cases, this is all said, I think when
you talk a lot about moes, it's really
really hard to forecast your moat going
forward. If you look back at all the
best businesses at the at the early
stages, they were they were just
thinking about, okay, I'm winning
customer trust. I'm selling more to them
and there's a lot of opportunity versus,
okay, I'm going to do these six steps
and then get to the seventh step and
then we'll have a moat. And so I think
we we talk a lot about defensibility and
durability. And I think part of that is
you're locking in the customer. They
there's more dependencies, they find it
valuable, and you're doing more of the
work. And here it's it's truly like
okay, you know, old CRM company was uh
log for all the deals. New sales AI
agent is actually owning a lot of the
sales prep process and the outbound
process fielding inbound and doing a
bunch of the work. um the comp the
overall customer is dependent on that
product and that's like a really
important signal of getting to the moat.
And everything we talk about in terms of
um in terms of stickiness and network
effects and all that is sort of
downstream of um of of that initial like
customer use and the value of the
product.
>> Yeah. Um Vlad, have have you had
conversations with customers or
potential customers who ask you, you
know, why should I buy your product? Why
can't I just, you know, plug into a
model and do this myself or like use
whatever existing system of record I
have plus a model? Um like like what
what do you tell them and and how do you
how do you convince them to to use Leo?
>> Yeah, 100%. And and that's a very fair
question, right? And like even if you
look like internally at LEO, so like the
the first use case 3 years ago which
like kind of like went viral in the
procurement world was like just like
having a quote and then getting this
information into SAP. So like very like
again like technically like but like
like tremendous business value. Um and
so you um you have like this retrieval
agent um getting like all of the
information putting it into SAP. We like
this was our like first product um and
we had an engineering team like
obviously small just like the three of
us or maybe like four people building it
um and then selling it but this is
nowadays a case study um if you if
you're applying to work at LEO so we
give this to people like to build this
and they have like 8 hours to do so. So
what I want to say by that is like a
product that we like one of our first
use cases um can now be somehow built by
engineers within 8 hours. Um so because
it's very easy to build stuff nowadays.
Um so obviously there's a question okay
well so someone can build this within
eight hours. Okay cool but then couldn't
like just procurement department
partners also just build everything in 2
months. Um and the answer is like yes
you can build this in 8 hours and you
can build this but you will only reach
70% let's say like the of the
performance. Um and the problem is 70%
of performance or accuracy or however
you measure it. It depends really on the
task doesn't mean 70% um automation,
right? So it's it's this can be mean
that you're like have 70% of the
performance but you still need to do
100% 100% of the work um because 70% is
not not that much. So again like all of
the people have to um have to check the
data. Um, so maybe you even created like
more work um more work than um than you
did before.
>> Two things to to layer on to what Vlad
just said. One um overall it's good if
there's more adoption of the base models
or just like GPT products because it
means that people are also willing to
trust um vertical specific products as
well. So I think that increased uh
familiarity, comfort, excitement about
AI tools is generally just good for the
market. Um the second thing is I was
chatting with the management team of a
Fortune 500 company two or three weeks
ago and um one of the things they
mentioned was they had tried to build
out their own cash collection uh
product. This is a big enterprise
business and they like after I I don't
know three or four months of work at a
minimum they had found that there wasn't
enough context. There was poor quality
context. They had a lot of recordings, a
lot of screen grabs. Um they tried to
pull it all into one system, but they
there was no um there they wasn't good
enough. Uh and then there was this giant
question around okay like you know we've
got now two different ERPs and we were
about to acquire another one. Um who's
going to update all the mappings test
the you know test out okay does it work?
Um and then like we keep talking about
exception handling. You now need to map
that onto a totally different system a
different way of doing things. And I
think they quickly realized that the
internal build didn't make sense. And so
we keep hearing stories of this where
people are like okay I'm going to do the
internal build. and they're like, "Wait
a second, it's not different from what
DIY's ever been in the past, which
corporates have always tried." But, um,
I think enterprise companies generally
realize that like there there's their
core competency and then there's, um,
building internal tools and, um, they
should focus on the the first camp.
Yeah. Yeah. Makes sense. Um,
>> yeah. So, that's exactly what I what
I've meant with like obviously like they
can they can get to 80%, but those last
20% really matter. um and you can only
get like they matter to get into
production. So that's why you need like
this harness, right? So you need all
those like integrations memory workflows
and sometimes you need vertical data um
um to do that and like like like the
parto princip so like those 20% can make
like 80% of the of the effort um or like
they are making 80% of the effort um so
like to all like those fortune 500 150
companies so you can do this um but then
let's say like procurement and workforce
of AI procurement agents should then
become like one of your core
competencies. Um, and you should
evaluate whether this makes sense or not
for you um to to have this in as like
your core skill.
>> Um, Vlad, I'm curious if you're seeing
suppliers start to use agents or AI at
all and kind of like what happens when
both the buyers and the suppliers are
are fully AI enabled.
>> Yeah. So like we 100% believe that like
in the future there will be like agents
on both sides. Um and um this this makes
so much sense. Um but like surprisingly
what we what we see is like so like when
we look at the supplier side this also
kind of like equals the seller side
right. So what we see is like that the
the sales side was like always ahead of
the procurement side. Um but what we're
now seeing with those suppliers for this
Fortune 500 companies um this actually
is not true. So they are like maybe
advanced in like let's say um video
recordings and like using tools like
granola and all all on all the stuff but
like not like really um having agents
deployed they're automating the work um
and the cool thing is is like
procurement is like is unsexy right so
sales is sexy procurement is unsexy but
it's like one process and procurement is
the the counterpart but now the good
thing is in those industrial companies
for 5000 companies
Procurement has the bigger power to the
supplier because you as an like typical
use case like automotive supplier you
dictate to your suppliers what they
should use what the quality has to be um
how they have to how they have to answer
to an specific RFQ. Um so the
opportunity is now if we serve the
procurement department and then can and
they can dictate what a supplier should
use. um why are we not like not like why
aren't we like also pushing them to like
LEO agents um that are also helping them
automate the work um owning then both
sides of um of the transaction
>> and Elena I know we were talking earlier
today about you know how can you have
two parties on the same platform is how
does that work um I think it could even
extended to like legal work right and
and these are two very adversarial
parties right but like if you have two
law firms with clients with different
interests, but both benefit from
knowing, okay, here's the latest draft.
Here's where we are with the open
issues. Here are things that have been
agreed upon. And just even tracking that
that doesn't doesn't really exist right
now, right? That's all being human
that's being created by um humans. And
so being that coordination effort an
agent could be doing.
>> Yum. Yum. It's well, it's super cool to
think about how like, you know, both
sides are kind of maybe evolving in
tandem. one side might be going a little
bit faster as you're talking about Vlad.
Um, but over time potentially people are
just like on the same platform and
actually it's like it's way better
coordinated for for everyone
>> 100%. Because like like also like what
we mentioned in the beginning, right? So
like like the obvious like the obvious
question is like okay but like we we
also talked a lot about like negotiation
agents. What if like both parties have
negotiation agents and price is 100% a
point where it's like a zero something
or like they have like different
interests. Um but we what we also
discuss is that like price is like the
outcome of like 5,000 different like
other task that happened and on those
5,000 other tasks they have the same
incentive. Um sales wants to have as
less like little friction as possible.
Um, buyers want to have a really fast
time to market, right? Again, like
coming back to building aircrafts,
building data centers. You want this
data center to be built as fast as
possible. You don't want to be build it
like 6 months later just because it
takes so much time um to analyze all of
the um responses from suppliers. Um, and
you want to make the sale also fast. So
like all of those five 5,000 other
tasks, the incentive is ex exactly the
same. And that's why you can deploy or
Leo can deploy agents also on both sides
um doing like automating the work um of
all those other tasks. Um this is the
beautiful thing.
>> I think that there used to be this logic
of like you shouldn't customize your
software too much to to one end user or
one end customer. But I think something
about LLMs and AI in general is like it
might increasingly be possible to
customize without slowing yourself down
as a business too much. Um, so I'm
curious if if that is something that
you're seeing Vlad or Sema um and and
kind of what what does that mean for for
end buyers of software? I think the
overall principle there's a lot of
forward deployed work happening right
now and part of that is because the
state of the customer data and
understanding
customer N um is a lot harder than
understanding N plus1 and so we're sort
of in the early stages of deployment
overall and that's why there's still a
lot of humans as part of this product um
and by the way that is something that is
harder for the incumbents to do because
they're also like not set up in in a way
to have even their the way their product
feedback cycle works where they have a
they have implementation teams but
that's very much an afterthought versus
something that feeds into the product
side. The beauty of AI is a it learns
over time. So that's when we're talking
about learning loops and you have the
right eval process, you can do more and
more complicated jobs over time and part
of that is automating the deployment
itself. And so you can and and I'd be
curious to hear how Vlad is doing it,
but a lot of our companies even are
doing that at you know at a rapid clip
where more of the customization a is
being handled in an automated way and b
the customer is able to turn the knobs
and levers around customization via
software um versus okay I needed to
bring in a the original it was like you
know you brought in Accenture to do your
SAP customization and now it's like
Okay, I've got a forward deployed team
that's going to build some, you know,
help build and spec it out. And
ultimately, it's going to be completely
software driven.
>> Yeah. Um I mean that's the reason why
like when you look at the or structure
of LEO, like 85% of the people are um
engineers. Um and even if you look at
like the people where you like they
don't have an engineering title, they
have like mostly like an engineering
background. And reason for that is um we
obviously like we don't want to be a
consulting company right so we make sure
that we have like overall the best um
agents in indirect and direct and
finance um and those part but then like
as you mentioned like there is a lot of
like forward deployed work um to do if
you go to enterprises because they have
like different nuances in their um in
their processes um but how we work is we
as you mentioned like building a product
in a way where it's like um where we
reducing this customization but also
where's a lot of like self-service. So
the job of our like FTDES and forward
deployed engineers um is on the one hand
making it like self-service but like in
internally is like automating their own
job right so like their KPI is like you
are seeing this happening like multiple
times like you like your literally your
job is like to automate yourself um and
then if you automate yourself you go to
the next task um I think it's like also
like an um approach that Google or so is
doing um so like but 100% agree with you
Um, and that's exactly what we are um
what we are building um and what how
we're doing it.
>> There was recently a a very big system
of record event and and we're not we're
not talking about Dreamforce, we're
talking about the the bots and buyers
summit that that Leo hosted in in New
York. Um and and just wanted to to kind
of hear, you know, stories from the
ground and and what what you're seeing
among buyers. What are people excited
about? what are people looking ahead
toward? What are people you know asking
you for? Um can you just kind of tell us
some stories from from that day and that
event?
>> So I mean it was the third time that we
are doing that we are doing this event.
Now we did it in um in New York just a
few blocks from our um from our office
here and over 100 procurement leaders
arrived right and what we like we made
sure that we like when we do when we do
such events that we only invite like
high caliber people right so like seale
co vice um vice president um and there
are like two things very like very
different um of of of how we do this or
like why why they're so amazed so the
first thing is um when we look at like
how procurement used to work in the last
26 27 years um a lot of tools emerge
right so you can like they're like all
those technology landscapes and you can
find them on LinkedIn you will see like
there are like 500 procurement tools but
like if you like and this is also the
reason like but when you talk to
procurement people like very painful and
like I challenge someone like to find
someone who like loves to work with
procurement like no one does like you
can really state people hate working
with procurement and we're talking about
the requesters and we're talking about
the suppliers and even people in
procurement hate working on procurement.
Um so like what's going on if there are
like 1,000 tools? Um and the reason for
that is like the all of the tools. Um um
they just made the the process more
efficient. That's that's all. But they
never changed how though how those
people actually work. Um, and it's like
crazy to see that they work in emails
and in Microsoft Teams there's and in
Excel sheets and powerpoints. like their
main channel where they work on and it's
like zero like zero AI enabled um
obviously um um in in in this part and
the the other thing is like we um we
give them like a very cross department
perspective on procurement right so we
are not talking about like look at this
crazy invoice feature that we developed
but we more looking like like someone
needs something um and in the end you
have it on your table and this can be
like a cross indirect direct, logistics,
finance and you can see how we are doing
it here and we also putting it into like
more into like a physical world because
like AI agents that's very abstract um
so what we are doing is we building up
booths and we we even have this in our
offices um in um also in New York where
you can walk through the booths and
experience like um all of those agents
like really hands-on um and that's what
the what's what what the people love and
it's like um I mean the next event um
will be with around 700 people. Um so
you can imagine how how crazy this this
grows.
>> Procurement people gone wild. Yeah.
Yeah. It's going to be that one is in um
Munich.
>> Um yeah. So we doing them like in um in
Europe Munich and in New York um all the
time. Yeah.
>> Cool. If you're listening and in
procurement, you know where to go. Maybe
I guess one question uh one question for
me. What do you think it takes to get uh
to to get people excited about
procurement? Is it is it the agents? Is
it the people? Is it the time saved?
Like what or like something else like
you mentioned it like procurement is one
of these things that I I I remember you
know people aren't they don't like it
like it's like a universally kind of
disliked low NPS area. I remember
talking to a guy who was out of
procurement like I don't know seven or
eight years ago as I was looking at this
category and he was like h I hate
talking about this product like I I use
you know this legacy system of record.
I'm on Koopa and I don't I don't want to
buy anything else. I don't want to talk
about it. It's fine. It was like the
most disgruntled customer call I've ever
done out of like millions of them. Um
but I'm I'm curious uh yeah what it is
that you think you know really gets
people excited about this category.
>> Yeah. So I mean it's like it's like and
this is also why why why I like
procurement is like it's on one hand
like so like the reason like why we
started in procurement like it's not
essentially like what happened but like
how people react to it right so if you
talk to the to the people they're like
really frustrated so this means it's an
like highly emotional topic but it's
like like let's be honest like um B2B
Zars okay but it's like highly emotional
um so that's a good thing and then if
you combine this with um like something
which is boring and niche. Um this is
also an advantage because um again like
the it's um it's like also easy or easy
for us for to amaze those people, right?
Because like the the really last
revolution they have seen is like 20
years ago um and then maybe a nicer user
interface 10 years ago um but nothing
else happened. Um, and so you have like
boring, highly emotional and then plus
crazy business impact, right? So like it
feels like it's unnecessary, but like I
I told you like some examples. So like
it has like obviously crazy P&L impact,
but it has impact on like the whole
economy, right? So we're like we are
talking about like how data centers are
built, how aircrafts are built, how cars
are built, um how drones are built. So
it's extremely important that um you
have a fixed procurement process um not
only to like make it happen and build
something um but then also when you talk
about like when we when you look at like
the competitive landscape so to get like
1% margin increase um you need to make
10% more revenue 10% more sales um so
like if you just manage to get like 1%
savings it's like equals like 10% of
sales um that you have to
um to get the same outcome in your P&L.
Um so like it's tremendously important
and like you combine all of those three
things and then you have like um a
trillion dollar business opportunity.
That's that's my opinion like for
procurement, but there are probably also
like other things that like emotional,
boring, and have a crazy business
impact.
>> Well, Vlad, thank you so much for
joining us. Uh this was a ton of fun.